Jacob Malmstadt

Innovative software engineer with 2+ years of experience. Eager to join to help develop reliable solution software. Previous accomplishments include increasing code efficiency at Syfer Strategies by 70% and helped facilitate software at call centers during COVID-19. Led the SCRUM activities for the senior project allowing for the SCRUM team of 4 to graduate. An empathetic team player, creative and critical thinker.

Professional Experience

ScienceLogic | Remote Software Developer | December 2021 - March 2023

- Spearheaded the refactoring and fixing of vital Python scripts used for Oracle Container databases and Google Cloud Platform, providing customers with working troubleshooting scripts used for pinpointing issues they were having, reducing customer interaction by over 50%.
- Volunteered to participate with senior developers during support calls, directly working with the customer, solving issues in services including, Oracle, VMware, Google Cloud Platform, etc.
- Navigated SCRUM ceremonies with a team of 8, undertaking the software development life cycle for 10 bespoke client projects.
- Completed QA tasks using industry standard tools, Jenkins and Python unit tests, resulting in reliable quality assurance testing
- Managed time well to deliver high quality products to more than 100 different customers, ensuring customer satisfaction.
- Undertook the hybrid role of being a QA Engineer while simultaneously cross training and participating in Python Developer work, learning to develop meaningful solutions.

Syfer Strategies, LLC | Vancouver, Washington Software Developer | September 2020 - December 2021

- Developed multiple business scripts and applications, utilizing exceptional expertise in Python, resulting in the development of 10-20 business scripts and applications to provide new features/automation services
- Refactored 1000 lines of code down to 300 lines solving the monolithic code issue my employer was having.
- Converted a simple flat structured code base into a multiservice Docker Compose stack, resulting in code modularity and the removal of code dependencies.
- Configured and built an automation application through strategic thinking and operational efficiency, that streamlined the Cisco CUCM application needed in response to Covid-19 related events surrounding Contact Center Agent configuration
- Adeptly created a multitude of Grafana dashboards through strong analytical and knowledge of industry standards/best practices, improving observability to properly describe the data in visual form

Education/Certifications

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Western Oregon University 2017 - 2020

Associate of Art (Transfer Degree)

Clatsop Community College 2015 - 2017

Skills

- 2 years Python
- 1 year C#
- 1 year SQL
- 1 year MySQL
- 1 year BitBucket
- 4 years Git
- 1 year Docker
- React
- Node
- Time Management
- Problem-Solving
- Teamwork
- Communication

Additional Information

https://github.com/theMalmstadt/Ok_Computer | Monmouth, Oregon Senior Capstone Project - Ok Bracket Manager | April 2020 - June 2020

- Contributed in full stack development on an Agile Development team utilizing expert knowledge in front end and database development, with focus on rendering accuracy and productivity
- Adequately used HTML, CSS, JS, with C# Razor Pages for front end development and demonstrated the use of C# and SQL with Microsoft Server, all while under the .NET Framework and MVC 5 architecture.
- Partnered with 3 team members for 10-12 weeks using two week sprints, utilizing a strong relationship building and project management background, reaching timeline target management goal
- Successfully performed a SCRUM/GitHub Master role for the SCRUM team through consistent research and analysis, accurately approving and denying pull requests

Math Club Vice President - Western Oregon University